Christopher B. Duffy

1332 Valley Brook Avenue, Sacramento, CA 95831 | 916.601.9721 | Christopher.B.Duffy@gmail.com ChrisDuffyPortfolio.com | github.com/Christopher-Duffy

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

I am a software engineer with graphic design and user experience design skills. I specialize in full stack web development. I am motivated by building complex web applications that solve difficult problems, look great, and are easy to use.

EDUCATION

M.S. in Computer Science

Columbus, GA

Columbus State University Georgia

Aug 2021

GPA: 3.91 **Coursework**: Algorithms & Data Structures, Operating Systems, Networks, Design Patterns **Technologies:** C, C#, Java, Python, HTML/CSS, Javascript, Oracle SQL, Postgres, MongoDB, Django, Node.js

B.A. in Computer in Modeling and Animation

Sacramento, CA

May 2019

California State University Sacramento

Sacramento. CA

A.A. in Communication Sacramento City College

May 2016

User Experience Specialist Certification

Nielsen Norman Group

July 2020

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer

Sacramento. CA

California Department of Water Resources

Sept 2020 - Current

- Worked with designers, users, developers, and administrators to develop complex web applications
 - Developed and maintained the EDD web standards using HTML, CSS, JS, and BootStrap
 - Insured digital accessibility of products was ADA compliant and met the standards of WCAG 2.1 and Section 508
 - Designed front-end apps and positive user experiences using graphic design, user research, and heuristic review
 - Acted as a project lead to guarantee project goals and requirements were met while staving on schedule

User Experience Designer

Sacramento, CA

July 2019 - Sept 2020

Employment Development Department

- Worked with designers, users, developers, and administrators to develop complex web applications
- Developed and maintained the EDD web standards using HTML, CSS, JS, and BootStrap
- Designed front-end apps and positive user experiences using graphic design, user research, and heuristic review
- Leveraged Knowledge of HTML/CSS, Javascript, Graphic Design, User Experience Design

Web Developer *GEI Consultants*

Rancho Cordova, CA

June 2015 - Sept 2017

Developed applications using Java, Oracle SQL, Apache Tomcat, and HTML/CSS, among other technologies

- Wrote, maintained, tested, debugged, and documented code independently and within a development team
- Built GIS mapping applications to display critical hydrological data and projected data models
- Implemented Python scripts to process and analyze large datasets for google earth visualizations
- Worked with real time data, large datasets, and simulated models to create easily understood data visualizations
- Leveraged knowledge of HTML/CSS, Javascript, Java, SQL, Python, C#